Anna Chernova

Junior Software Developer

Location: Folkestone, England Mob: 07481 492 432 Email: annanvks@gmail.com

> GitHub: Anna702 LinkedIn: annache

Profile:

I'm a novice **software developer** with a 15-year background in journalism and PR.

After graduating from a Northcoders Software Development bootcamp in 2023, I dove into the world of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React/React Native. Then I hungered for more knowledge and enrolled in a Front-end Development bootcamp with EdX.

I'm on a mission to merge my storytelling power with tech skills and become a pro at creating **user-friendly and valuable apps**. Let's connect and create something awesome together!

Technical Skills:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, React, React Native, Firebase, EXPO, Express, jQuery, Canva, Figma

Professional Experience:

EdX 11/2023 – present

Front-End Web Development Bootcamp Trainee

I am currently enrolled in EdX Front-End Web Development Skills Bootcamp. Upon completion of the program in March 2024, I will have learned how to develop websites using the latest web standards, code with modern HTML5 tags, design web pages using CSS best practices, and develop interactive web apps using JavaScript. Additionally, I will have a deep understanding jQuery, React.js and Node. The course also provides a comprehensive overview of application programming interfaces (APIs), user experience design, and building and deploying modern web applications.

Northcoders 01/2023 – 04/2023

Coding Bootcamp Trainee

I studied software development during the 13-week Coding Bootcamp.

During this time, I became familiar with a test-driven development, pair programming, object-oriented programming and a range of other core tools and workplace practices through JavaScript. I used Node.js and React.js, looked at APIs and databases, started to use Express and SQL.

Projects:

GrinAndGin

As part of our Front-End Web Development Skills Bootcamp, this app was designed to simplify cocktail mixing and culinary pairing.

Deployed app:

https://anna702.github.io/GrinAndGin

GitHub repo:

https://github.com/Anna702/GrinAndGin

Personal portfolio created with Bootstrap

Deployed app:

https://anna702.github.io/Bootstrap Portfolio/

GitHub repo:

https://github.com/Anna702/Bootstrap Portfolio

Self-Employed, 08/2018 – 01/2023

Maternity leave

Time spent during maternity leave: writing commercial articles, editing videos for a personal blog and social media development consulting.

Pulse UK, London 10/2015 – 08/2018

Journalist/Commercial Writer

Creating content for a weekly newspaper in London (researching and reporting on current events, producing in-depth articles for print and online publications, editing and fact-checking). Working with advertisers, writing promotional articles. Growing newspaper presence on social media.

Broadcasting company 'MIR'

06/2010 - 02/2013

Producer/Journalist

Firstly, I was responsible for coordinating with guests, crew and other stakeholders to ensure a smooth production. Also, I was directing and supervising shoots, researching and developing stories, as well as conducting interviews in person and remote. Finally, supervising the post-production process was an important part of my work as well.

Other Employment

I also have proven experience as a PR manager, radio screenwriter and commercial writer. As a part of a team, I was creating content for such brands as Bavaria, Efes, Ehrmann, Fiat and Bosch. I also enjoyed working as a Project Manager with musicians and music festivals.

Qualification:

Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Russia

Qualification: journalist, course: Journalism (5 years)

Right to work:

- United Kingdom (settled status, eligible to work in the UK)
- EU (Italian citizenship)
- Russia (Russian citizenship)